<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-08T23:10:35+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Masahiro Ono</title><subtitle>Masahiro Ono is an Integrative Experimental and Computational Immunologist. He is known as the creator and developer of the innovative Timer-of-Cell-Kinetics-and-Activity (Tocky) technology. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Unsung Roles of HTLV-1 in the Discovery of CD25 and Treg</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/CD25/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Unsung Roles of HTLV-1 in the Discovery of CD25 and Treg"/><published>2024-06-21T01:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-21T01:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/CD25</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/CD25/"><![CDATA[<div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> CD4+ T cells (Green). Some express Foxp3 (Red) as well. Nucleus is stained by DAPI (blue). Credit Masahiro Ono. </div> <hr/> <h4 id="the-leukaemia-inducing-retrovirus">The Leukaemia-Inducing Retrovirus</h4> <p>Human T-cell Leukemia Virus Type 1 (HTLV-1) affects certain regions worldwide, such as South Japan, the Caribbean, and parts of Africa. This virus, sharing infection routes similar to HIV, targets CD4+ T cells. Unlike HIV, HTLV-1 does not cause these cells to die off or diminish in number. Instead, in some individuals, it transforms these cells, leading to a rare and severe form of leukemia known as Adult T-cell leukemia/lymphoma (ATL). Others may develop a type of neuroinflammation known as HTLV-1-associated myelopathy/tropical spastic paraparesis (HAM/TSP).</p> <p>Research into HTLV-1 and ATL has played a crucial role in the discovery of regulatory T cells (Tregs), although this contribution is currently underappreciated. In this article, I aim to detail some of the historical developments where HTLV-1 studies not only preceded but also facilitated the discovery of CD25, leading to the discovery of Treg.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="development-of-anti-cd25-antibody-using-cells-from-htlv-1-induced-leukemia">Development of Anti-CD25 Antibody Using Cells From HTLV-1-Induced Leukemia</h4> <p>One groundbreaking finding from ATL research was the cloning of the IL-2 receptor alpha chain gene, known as CD25. This discovery stemmed from the inability to culture ATL cells without high doses of IL-2, strongly suggesting these cells had high IL-2 receptor expression.</p> <p>Indeed, using ATL cells, researchers hypothesized this and created a specific monoclonal antibody, namely the <em>anti-Tac antibody</em>, which was produced by Dr Takashi Uchiyama. The clone name of the antibody was from Dr Uchiyama’s first name, Takashi.</p> <p><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12185-010-0664-z">The obituary article</a> by Prof Kiyoshi Takatsuki, the discoverer of the ATL disease, details Dr Uchiyama’s work life and his dedication for ATL and administration in Kyoto University.</p> <p>In 1984, with Dr Uchiyama, the Nobel Laureate Prof Tasuku Honjo led the study to clone the previously unknown IL-2 receptor gene, which led to the successful cloning of the CD25 (Il2ra) gene <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/311631a0">(Nikaido et al, 1984)</a>.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/htlv/CD25-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/htlv/CD25-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/htlv/CD25-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/htlv/CD25.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="800" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Human IL2RA gene (CD25). </div> <hr/> <h4 id="cloning-of-cd25-il2ra-il-2-receptor-alpha-chain">Cloning of CD25, IL2RA (IL-2 Receptor Alpha Chain)</h4> <p>Using the anti-Tac antibody and the cloned CD25 sequence, researchers revealed that any T cells express CD25 when activated; most ATL cells show constant high expression.</p> <p>This led to the creation of CD25 knockout mice. Researchers anticipated that the knockout mice would show severe immunosuppression as CD25 could not be used and T-cells would not be properly activated.</p> <p>However, surprisingly, the CD25 knockout mice developed autoimmune inflammation, rather than immunosuppression. This strongly suggests CD25’s role in immune regulation, rather than in the induction of T cell response.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="the-discovery-of-cd25-tregs-in-the-90s-lost-opportunities-in-research-development">The Discovery of CD25+ Tregs in the 90s: Lost Opportunities in Research Development</h4> <p>The discovery of CD25 and the knockout phenotype spurred further investigations into CD25+ CD4+ T cells throughout the 90s. Key developments during this period laid the foundations of Treg research, determining the direction of subsequent studies.</p> <p>However, these studies in the 90s characterized Tregs as a ‘unique’ population of T-cells that physiologically develop during neonatal periods and failed to fully appreciate an important aspect of T-cell biology: cellular and molecular dynamics. This oversight was not due to technological limitations of the time but rather to specific unfortunate historical developments. These issues continue to impact the current research landscape. I will explore these critical issues in detail in the context of the discovery of CD25+ Tregs in my next article.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="further-reading">Further Reading</h4> <p>For those interested in delving deeper into the link between CD25 and HTLV-1, please read our recent publication <a class="citation" href="#10.1093/discim/kyae006">(Ono &amp; Satou, 2024)</a>.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="some-of-my-own-memories-for-htlv-1-and-the-anti-tac-antibody">Some of My Own Memories For HTLV-1 and the Anti-Tac Antibody</h4> <p>I had a fortunate medical education with more than half of the virology lectures dedicated to HTLV-1 and ATL; molecular biology lectures were mostly delivered by Prof Honjo.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/htlv/Honjo-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/htlv/Honjo-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/htlv/Honjo-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/htlv/Honjo.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="600" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Prof Tasuku Honjo and Myself at European Congress of Immunology, 2018, in Amsterdam. </div> <p>Further, I was trained in dermatology in Kyoto University under the strong influence of Prof Uchiyama’s discoveries and achievements: the detection of elevated levels of soluble CD25 by anti-Tac antibody can help in the diagnosis and monitoring of ATL patients.</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="CD25"/><category term="HTLV-1"/><category term="ATL"/><category term="Treg"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How CD25 and Treg were discovered through HTLV-1]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">tocky illuminates mechanisms of immune checkpoint blockade</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/CancerImmunotherapy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="tocky illuminates mechanisms of immune checkpoint blockade"/><published>2024-06-09T01:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-09T01:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/CancerImmunotherapy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/CancerImmunotherapy/"><![CDATA[<p>In 2017, after successfully developing the Tocky technology and the data transformation method for Tocky data, I began submitting our first Tocky papers. Around the same time, I launched a new cancer immunotherapy project that utilized the capabilities of Tocky technology.</p> <h3 id="a-pump-priming-collaborative-grant-2017">A Pump Priming Collaborative Grant 2017</h3> <p>In 2016, I initiated discussions about a new cancer immunotherapy project with my collaborators at the Institute for Cancer Research, Prof Alan Melcher and Prof Kevin Harrington.</p> <p>These discussions led to securing a pump-priming grant from the <em>Cancer Research Centre of Excellence</em> (CRCE, now known as the <em>CRUK Convergence Science Centre</em>). The grant, which was for a one-year project starting in September 2017, marked a significant milestone. It enabled us to commence a project focused on investigating the effects of immune checkpoint blockade on cancer-reactive T cells, utilizing tools such as Nr4a3-Tocky and Foxp3-Tocky.</p> <h3 id="a-phd-studentship-2019">A PhD studentship 2019</h3> <p>The next stage of our cancer research endeavor involved applying for a PhD studentship from the Convergence Science Centre to study immune checkpoint inhibitors, specifically PD-1 blockade. This application was successful, leading to the launch of <a href="https://www.convergencesciencecentre.ac.uk/research/research-impact/studentship-projects">a new PhD studentship project dedicated to investigating the mechanisms of immune checkpoint blockade using the Tocky tools</a>.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cruk/2019studentship-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cruk/2019studentship-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cruk/2019studentship-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cruk/2019studentship.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="600" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> The studentship project that recruited a new cross-institutional PhD student in 2019. </div> <p>This project aimed to enhance the precision of cancer immunotherapy by exploring T cell regulation mechanisms in melanoma patients. With the establishment of Tocky technology, the project focused on two critical immune suppressors: PD-1 and regulatory T cells (Treg). It sought to reveal the mechanisms behind anti-PD-1 and anti-CTLA-4, which have become standard treatments in malignant melanoma and other cancers.</p> <h3 id="cruk-programme-foundation-award-2021">CRUK Programme Foundation Award 2021</h3> <p>In pursuit of substantial funding to fully launch my cancer immunotherapy project, I encountered several challenges. Despite these struggles, my persistent efforts culminated in a successful application for a CRUK Programme Foundation Award (PFA).</p> <p>The pivotal interview for this award took place on March 10, 2020, just before the onset of the first lockdown in the UK.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cruk/lockdown-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cruk/lockdown-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cruk/lockdown-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cruk/lockdown.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="450" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> The corner with toilet rolls in a supermarket near the interview venue on 10th March 2020. </div> <p>I left the interview with a positive feeling, but I had to wait for the announcement of the results, which was unusually delayed by almost a year due to the pandemic.</p> <h3 id="first-collaboration-paper-published-2021">First Collaboration Paper Published 2021</h3> <p>In the meantime, our first collaborative paper on cancer immunotherapy with the Institute for Cancer Research (ICR) was successfully published in 2021 <a class="citation" href="#RN80">(Bozhanova et al., 2022)</a>. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/jitc-2021-004410">This study</a> explored the mechanism of an oncolytic virus therapy using Nr4a3-Tocky technology.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cruk/ov-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cruk/ov-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cruk/ov-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cruk/ov.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="450" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> The first collaboration paper with Profs Melcher and Harrington at ICR published in 2021. </div> <h3 id="first-preprint-released-in-july-2022">First Preprint Released in July 2022</h3> <p>Our first study on cancer immunotherapy, focusing on immune checkpoint blockade, was made available as a preprint in July 2022<a class="citation" href="#RN83">(Hassan et al., 2022)</a>. This was more delayed than anticipated due to the challenging periods during the pandemic and personal circumstances. Still, this was an important milestone for us.</p> <p>This research explored the mechanisms of <strong>the anti-PD-L1 and anti-CTLA-4 antibodies</strong> using <strong>Nr4a3-Tocky</strong> technology. The findings led us to hypothesize and test the <strong>anti-OX40 antibody</strong>, which demonstrated significant additive effects on anti-cancer T-cell activities.</p> <p>I am grateful to my great collaborators, Prof Alan Melcher and Prof Kevin Harrington at ICR, and Prof Taku Okazaki, who is a renowned expert in PD-1 and Lag-3 biology.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cruk/biorxiv-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cruk/biorxiv-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cruk/biorxiv-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cruk/biorxiv" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="750" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Hassan et al reveals the effects of PD1 blockade, CTLA-4 blockade, and anti-OX40 immunotherapy on T cell activities using Nr4a3 Tocky <a class="citation" href="#RN83">(Hassan et al., 2022)</a>. </div> <p>The endeavor has just begun. We anticipate being able to discuss the full scale of our cancer immunotherapy project within this blog very soon.</p> <hr/> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="PD1"/><category term="CTLA4"/><category term="OX40"/><category term="cancer"/><category term="immunotherapy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[our cancer immunotherapy Tocky projects]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">t-cell dynamics matter</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/TGN1412/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="t-cell dynamics matter"/><published>2024-06-07T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-07T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/TGN1412</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/TGN1412/"><![CDATA[<img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="750" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tgn1412/tregactivation-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tregactivation-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tregactivation-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tgn1412/tregactivation.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="750" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Use the slider function to experience how the Treg story gradually dominated and deviated the basic understanding of T cell biology, culminating in the catastrophic TGN1412 trial. </div> <h3 id="lessons-from-the-first-treg-immunotherapy-trial">Lessons from the First Treg Immunotherapy Trial</h3> <p>Regulatory T cells (Tregs) are suppressor cells by definition. Usual T cells induce immune response when they recognise their target. However, Tregs can suppress immune response. Thus the current theory is that Tregs are a special type of T cells, functioning to maintain immune system balance and prevent autoimmune diseases, where the body attacks its own cells.</p> <p>However, these T cells aren’t as unique as people believe. This is illustrated in the catastrophic clinical trial for the world-first clinical trial, TGN1412 <a class="citation" href="#RN58">(Bending &amp; Ono, 2018)</a>.</p> <h4 id="the-clinical-trial">The Clinical Trial</h4> <p>The significance of understanding T cells’ dynamics in vivo is illuminated by the clinical trial of TGN1412 in 2006. TGN1412, a superagonistic anti-CD28 antibody intended to suppress autoimmune reactions, instead caused severe inflammation known as a “cytokine storm” in volunteers.</p> <h4 id="turning-point">Turning Point</h4> <p>TGN1412 is a superagonistic anti-CD28 antibody designed to activate T cells directly, eliminating the need for anti-CD3 antibodies. Initially, it was developed with the goal of activating and restoring the T-cell repertoire in leukaemia patients. However, following promising results from animal studies, TGN1412 was later repurposed as an immunosuppressant. These studies showed that the anti-CD28 stimulation selectively activated regulatory T cells (Tregs) and effectively suppressed immune response.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tgn1412/tgn1412-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tgn1412-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tgn1412-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tgn1412/tgn1412.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="600" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Summary of Research and Development Strategies for TGN1412. </div> <h4 id="investigations-and-reflections">Investigations and Reflections</h4> <p>Investigations into the incident concluded that it was an unfortunate and unforeseeable event due to the different expression dynamics of CD28 between humans and primates, which were used in the pre-clinical stage of the drug development.</p> <p>However, as discussed in Vitetta and Ghetie (2006), <strong>Tregs and non-Tregs may not represent strictly separate lineages</strong>. Therefore, the assumption of specifically activating only a minor population may have been inappropriate.</p> <p>It is worth remembering that the first lecture in T cell biology always begins with T cell receptor signaling and CD28 signaling. Without CD28 signaling, T cells cannot be fully activated, as CD28 signaling is a strong activating signal for all T cells.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tgn1412/tcellactivation" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="600" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Adapted from My Lecture Slide for Introducting T-cell Biology. </div> <p>This disaster underscored the importance of understanding the roles and activation mechanisms of T cells in general, not just focusing on Treg cells alone.</p> <h4 id="foxp3-and-the-lieage-perspective">Foxp3 and the Lieage Perspective</h4> <p>Asano <em>et al</em> set the stage for the lineage perspective of Treg by highlighting CD25+CD4+ T cells as a “<em>naturally differentiated, unique T cell subset originating in the thymus</em>.” My other article showed that this perspective was not supported by reproducible evidence at the time.</p> <p>However, the subsequent development in immunology—the discovery of Foxp3—fit well with the stage set by Asano <em>et al</em>. Foxp3, as a transcription factor specifically expressed by CD25+CD4+ T cells, was defined as the lineage-determinant factor of Tregs.</p> <p>It is true that Foxp3 is key in controlling the development and function of suppressive T cells. However, by defining Foxp3 as the lineage factor, we overlook an essential aspect of T cells – their dynamic nature and changing properties.</p> <h4 id="treg-plasticity-or-changing-t-cells">Treg Plasticity or Changing T cells?</h4> <p>Recent studies have highlighted the plasticity of Tregs—that is, their ability to change under certain conditions. For example, during inflammation, Tregs can lose their Foxp3 expression and transform into effector T cells, which actively respond to pathogens. This plasticity is crucial because it demonstrates that Tregs can adapt based on the body’s needs, potentially shifting roles from regulators to attackers.</p> <p>However, by categorizing these changes as Treg <em>plasticity</em>, studies remain trapped and constrained by the lineage perspective. Indeed, many researchers and pharmaceutical companies are pursuing the development of a method to produce ‘stable’ Tregs.</p> <p><strong>What if Foxp3 is inherently a dynamic molecule? Is it an effective approach to pursue the stable Treg as a holy grail?</strong></p> <h4 id="from-stability-to-dynamics">From Stability To Dynamics</h4> <p>Revealing the principles of Foxp3 as a dynamic mechanism could significantly improve our ability to control the T cell system. However, this cannot be achieved if studies remain constrained by the lineage perspective that originated with Asano et al.</p> <p>Studying the dynamic changes in Tregs during immune responses is crucial for a deeper understanding of immune regulation. Innovative tools like the Tocky system, which tracks cell kinetics and activity, are enabling researchers to explore how Tregs and their Foxp3 expression change in real-time. These insights are vital for developing effective immunotherapies.</p> <p>Understanding the dynamics of Foxp3 and Treg activity provides a window into the sophisticated mechanisms of immune regulation. This knowledge is not only fundamental to the field of immunology but also crucial for developing new treatments for immune-related diseases.</p> <p>Investigating Foxp3 as a dynamic molecule and the dynamics of T cells in vivo within a broader context will be a fundamental approach not only for understanding T cell biology but also for developing future immunotherapies.</p> <p>The contents of this article are discussed in detail in <a href="https://academic.oup.com/cei/article/197/1/14/6402549">my paper published in 2019</a> and <a href="https://monotockylab.github.io/projects/2_project/">my blog article “Decoding Foxp3 – From Treg Dogma to T-cell Dynamics”</a>.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0 text-center"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tgn1412/newton-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tgn1412/newton-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tgn1412/newton-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tgn1412/newton.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="self-reactivity"/><category term="t-cells"/><category term="treg"/><category term="tgn1412"/><category term="immunotherapy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[lessons from the first treg immunotherapy trial]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">professionalism and official account integrity</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/dermatology/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="professionalism and official account integrity"/><published>2024-06-01T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-01T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/dermatology</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/dermatology/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="1-memories-of-dermatology">1. Memories of Dermatology</h4> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/jda/clinic-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/jda/clinic-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/jda/clinic-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/jda/clinic.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The photo is from 2001, in a clinic room located at the town hall, where I used to treat patients as a dermatologist. It was taken with my first digital camera, which I bought when I started practicing dermatology. It was quite expensive then and I needed to use my private budget, but I thought it was necessary for examining cases and improving my skills.</p> <p>This clinic was located in a suburb, and I visited every two weeks from the hospital where I worked in the city. My usual practice was very busy, with many on-call duties and frequent emergency calls.</p> <p>Despite this, I managed to squeeze in time for clinical studies. I would study at night in the dermatology room of the hospital, comparing old patient records and histopathology slides, often staying until morning.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/jda/hospital-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/jda/hospital-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/jda/hospital-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/jda/hospital.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h4 id="2-the-100th-annual-meeting-in-2001">2. The 100th Annual Meeting in 2001</h4> <p>In 2001, I attended the Annual Meeting of the Japanese Dermatological Association (JDA) for the first time. It was the 100th commemorative annual meeting, held at the Keio Plaza Hotel in Tokyo. It was a long way to travel by train to attend.</p> <p>At that time, I was intent on practicing dermatology, and attending the conference was enjoyable as I could learn various new things. I presented a case report on an intriguing fungal infection by <em>Alternaria Alternata</em> in the meeting, which was my first conference oral presentation.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <a href="https://academic.oup.com/bjd/article/150/4/773/6635548"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/jda/alternaria-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/jda/alternaria-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/jda/alternaria-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/jda/alternaria.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="600" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </a> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: left;"> The case report was later published as a correspondence article in the British Journal of Dermatology (BJD). </div> <p>The case I presented then led me to pursue a PhD in immunology starting the following year, which brings me to where I am today.</p> <h4 id="3-the-minami-award-the-107th-annual-meeting-in-2008">3. The Minami Award – the 107th Annual Meeting in 2008</h4> <p>After completing my PhD in an immunology lab in Kyoto University, I continued basic research in the same laboratory for a while. In 2008, I received the Minami Award at the Dermatology Conference and attended the meeting.</p> <p>I remember Professor Masayuki Amagai from Keio University, who is currently the head of the JDA, approaching me at the conference venue and encouraging me with these words: “Please continue your research in dermatology.”</p> <p>Indeed, I am still conducting research using experimental models of <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2022.07.19.500582v1">malignant melanoma</a> and <a href="https://monotockylab.github.io/projects/2_project/">allergic dermatitis</a>, which means some aspects of my work remain within the realm of dermatological science.</p> <h4 id="4-social-media-use-group-loyalty-and-professionalism-in-japan">4. Social Media Use, Group Loyalty, and Professionalism in Japan</h4> <h5 id="an-official-twitter-account-for-the-123th-annual-meeting-in-2023">An Official Twitter Account for the 123th Annual Meeting in 2023</h5> <p>Recently, on Twitter, <a href="https://x.com/masahirono/status/1790835624196354302">I raised issues with the management of the official account of the Japanese Dermatology Association (JDA)’s Annual Meeting 2024</a>.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <a href="https://x.com/masahirono/status/1790835624196354302"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/jda/tweet1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/jda/tweet1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/jda/tweet1-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/jda/tweet1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </a> </div> </div> <p>Here is a summary of my <a href="https://x.com/masahirono/status/1790835624196354302">initial tweets</a> for the JDA official account:</p> <p><em>“Japanese Dermatology Association Annual Meeting Account @jdakyoto: As a dermatology researcher in Japan, I’m concerned by the unprofessional trends in this account’s tweets. @jdakyoto seems focused on ‘nakama-ishiki’ (group loyalty). Shouldn’t an official account prioritize professional discourse? Effective social media use is about enhancing the conference’s professionalism, not cozying up. The @jdakyoto team needs to rethink its approach to uphold the conference’s integrity.”</em></p> <h5 id="aggravation">Aggravation</h5> <p>However, the subsequent actions have only deepened my disappointment due to increasingly deviant behaviors and further personalization of the account. Considering that <a href="https://x.com/jdakyoto">the official account</a> is operated by the Dermatology Department of Kyoto University, which is responsible for managing the 2024 annual meeting, I am compelled to question whether the conference itself is being managed in a similar manner.</p> <p>Thus, <a href="https://x.com/masahirono/status/1791765101524984073">I have once again asked the official account to reconsider</a>.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <a href="https://x.com/masahirono/status/1791765101524984073"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/jda/tweet2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/jda/tweet2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/jda/tweet2-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/jda/tweet2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </a> </div> </div> <p>Below is a summary of the main issues concerning the operation of the official Twitter account:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>A lack of consideration about how their actions appear publicly.</strong> The tweets to date have been sufficient to erode trust not only in the conference but in dermatologists in general from the public, such as patients.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>The official account, bearing the JDA’s logo and name, has been utilized for non-official purposes.</strong> These include promoting book sales by an individual from Kyoto University, which is responsible for the Annual Meeting 2024 and the official Twitter account, and introducing products sold by a dermatologist who apparently has a cozy relationship with the account.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>The official account was masquerading as a ‘funny event account’ or ‘Yuru-chara mascot’, ostensibly to justify its inappropriate content and stance.</strong> However, socially inappropriate actions cannot be justified under such pretenses.</p> </li> </ol> <p>Thus, these issues are related to management and governance, and the responsibility lies with the president of the Annual Meeting, Professor Kenji Kabashima of Kyoto University, and his management team.</p> <p>I believe that most members of the Dermatology Association will attend the conference, temporarily pausing their practices, just as I did 23 years ago. Many may need to do so to renew their specialist qualifications. I am confident that many members engage earnestly in the academic pursuit of dermatology. I hope the conference management team does not disappoint these dedicated professionals.</p> <p><strong>Note:</strong> This blog article was translated from a Japanese blog post originally published on May 18, 2024. Subsequently, some of the inappropriate posts were deleted by the official account <a href="https://x.com/jdakyoto">@jdakyoto</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="japan"/><category term="integrity"/><category term="dermatology"/><category term="kyoto"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[some thoughts on governance of a medical society]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the tocky bird</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/tockytori/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the tocky bird"/><published>2024-04-28T02:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T02:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/tockytori</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/tockytori/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="nipponia-nippon---the-bird-toki-朱鷺"><em>Nipponia Nippon</em> - The Bird Toki (朱鷺)</h3> <div class="row mt-3" style="text-align: center;"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="display: inline-block;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/TockyToki.jpg" width="350" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The Japanese Crested Ibis, known scientifically as <em>Nipponia Nippon</em>, is a member of the Threskiornithidae family. Historically common throughout East Asia, it has faced dramatic population declines due to habitat destruction and pollution.</p> <div class="row mt-3" style="text-align: center;"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="display: inline-block;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/NNphoto-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/NNphoto-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/NNphoto-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/NNphoto.jpg" width="350" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> Photo of Crested Ibis (<em>Nipponia nippon)</em> by Totti / <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%83%88%E3%82%AD#/media/%E3%83%95%E3%82%A1%E3%82%A4%E3%83%AB:Nipponia_nippon_Sado_Toki_Hogo_Center_2.jpg">CC BY-SA 4.0</a> </div> <p>In Japan, where the bird is culturally revered, conservation and reintroduction efforts have begun to bear fruit. The diet of the Toki consists predominantly of fish, frogs, and small creatures. With its striking white and pink plumage and gracefully curved bill, the <em>N. Nippon</em> is an emblematic figure.</p> <p>In a creative twist linking to the Tocky concept, the <em>Tocky Nipponia Nippon</em> is envisioned as a fantastical creature adorned in hues of blue and red, reminiscent of the transitions seen in the Fluorescent Timer protein used in the Tocky technology.</p> <div class="row mt-3" style="text-align: center;"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="display: inline-block;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/Tocky_Nipponia_Nippon-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/Tocky_Nipponia_Nippon-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/Tocky_Nipponia_Nippon-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/Tocky_Nipponia_Nippon.jpg" width="350" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;"> <em>Tocky Nipponia Nippon</em> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="tocky"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Tocky Tori]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">timer and tocky</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/timer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="timer and tocky"/><published>2024-03-30T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/timer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/timer/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="fluorescent-timer-protein">Fluorescent Timer Protein</h3> <p>As a BBSRC David Phillips Fellow, Dr. Ono developed a novel experimental method for analyzing the temporal changes in cellular activities and differentiation through flow cytometric analysis using a Fluorescent Timer protein, which was developed by the Verkhusha group (<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19136976/">Subach et al., 2009</a>). This Fluorescent Timer protein is an mCherry mutant (<em>fastFT</em>).</p> <p>The chromophore of the Fluorescent Timer protein emits blue fluorescence upon translation, which then matures into red chromophore with a half-life of 4 hours. This maturation process was <a href="https://www.embopress.org/doi/full/10.15252/embj.201899013">experimentally determined</a> through flow cytometric analysis of T-cells expressing the Timer protein <a class="citation" href="#RN56">(Bending et al., 2018)</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/timer/blue-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/timer/blue-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/timer/blue-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/timer/blue.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="300" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/timer/red-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/timer/red-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/timer/red-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/timer/red.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="300" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/bppb-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/bppb-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/bppb-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/bppb.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Left: Each Timer protein will emit either blue or red fluorescence (or be at the colorless stage). Right: figure from <a class="citation" href="#BPPB1">(Ono, 2024)</a>. </div> <hr/> <h3 id="from-timer-to-tocky-a-new-perspective">From Timer to Tocky: A New Perspective</h3> <p>With the Tocky reporter system, each cell expresses multiple Timer proteins. The expression dynamics are determined by the temporal dynamics of transcriptional activities for the Timer gene.</p> <p>Thus, each cell will express multiple Timer proteins, each maturing from the blue form to the red one. This creates a continuous gradient of Timer fluorescence from blue to red <a class="citation" href="#RN55">(Bending et al., 2018)</a>.</p> <p>As flow cytometry is a single-cell analysis method, the unique features of Timer fluorescence and Timer-expressing cells provide opportunities to dissect the temporal dynamics of cellular activities and differentiation.</p> <p>This requires quantitative analysis. Enter the quantitative Timer fluorescence analysis method - Tocky.</p> <p>Hence, the pivotal element that defines Tocky is the shift from protein-level analysis to <strong>single-cell level analysis</strong>.</p> <hr/> <div class="row mt-3"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tocky/cd4foxp3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="600" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="tocky"/><category term="immunology"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[the origin of tocky]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">journey to tocky via cca</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/cca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="journey to tocky via cca"/><published>2024-03-29T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/cca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/cca/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="transitioning-from-molecular-immunology-to-systems-immunology">Transitioning from Molecular Immunology to Systems Immunology</h4> <p>Until 2007, I focused on the molecular biology of Treg, publishing seminal papers for the Foxp3-Runx1 interaction <a class="citation" href="#RN23">(Ono et al., 2007)</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cca/nature-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cca/nature-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cca/nature-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cca/nature.jpg" width="500" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>However, upon realising the fundamental problem with Treg, I chose an unconventional path - extending my expertise to computational biology💻, which would become pivotal in developing Tocky.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="first-independent-studies-in-kyoto">First Independent Studies in Kyoto</h4> <p>As I was promoted to Assistant Professsor in 2007, I secured grant support from <a href="https://www.katokinen.or.jp/info/4_2english.html">the Kato Foundation</a> in 2008 for my first transcriptome analysis using microarray 🧬.</p> <p>However, the complexity of the data was overwhelming, challenging the simplistic analytical methods of the time.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cca/kato-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cca/kato-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cca/kato-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cca/kato.jpg" width="350" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="the-lack-of-appropriate-methods">The Lack of Appropriate Methods</h4> <p>Back then in 2006 - 2007, immunology papers mainly used simple methods like <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16772372/">log2 fold change only</a>, which was not convincing to me.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cca/sugimoto-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cca/sugimoto-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cca/sugimoto-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cca/sugimoto.jpeg" width="500" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="exploration-and-collaborations-in-kyoto">Exploration and Collaborations in Kyoto</h4> <p>Thus, in 2008, I aimed to develop more sophisticated methods for immunological genomic analysis, identifying Principal Component Analysis (PCA) as a promising candidate 🤔🔍.</p> <p>In 2008, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Dr_Kano">Dr Manabu Kano</a>, an expert in PCA in Eng. Dept, Kyoto Univ, provided invaluable guidance, teaching me mathematical foundations of PCA in data analysis.</p> <p>This collaboration was a pivotal step in my journey to redefine Treg in a data-oriented manner🎓💡.</p> <p>In addition, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/toshsugi">Prof Toshio Sugiman</a>, an expert in psychometrics🧠📈, introduced me to Hayashi’s Quantification Method III, a tool for quantifying <a href="https://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/acrt1992/1/1/1_1_17/_article">group relationships in psychology</a>.</p> <p>Hayashi’s statistical philosophy profoundly inspired me, and this will lead to the development of the groundbreaking method five years later.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="extending-research-fields-from-kyoto-to-the-uk">Extending Research Fields: From Kyoto to the UK.</h4> <p>Aiming to adapt Hayashi’s method and PCA for genomic data in immunology, I obtained an HFSP fellowship and thereby moved from Kyoto🇯🇵 to UCL🇬🇧 , eventually led to <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0053544">the development of Canonical Correspondence Analysis, originally by ter Braak, for genomics</a> <a class="citation" href="#RN98">(Ono et al., 2013)</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cca/plos-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cca/plos-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cca/plos-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cca/plos.jpeg" width="500" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>🔬Canonical Correspondence Analysis is an efficient method for [qunatitative anlaysis of cell phenotype and gene activities, focusing on certain biological processes]((https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2164-15-1028). In addition, it can classify cells using a machine learning approach <a class="citation" href="#RN97">(Ono et al., 2014)</a>🧬💻.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cca/genomics-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cca/genomics-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cca/genomics-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cca/genomics.jpeg" width="500" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="the-journey-to-tocky-is-through-cca">The Journey to Tocky is Through CCA</h4> <p>Importantly, CCA was utilized to identify <a href="https://rupress.org/jcb/article/217/8/2931/39442/A-timer-for-analyzing-temporally-dynamic-changes">Nr4a3 as the best correlate to TCR signalling</a>, which was a key step in developing Nr4a3-Tocky <a class="citation" href="#RN55">(Bending et al., 2018)</a> 🐭🔬.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cca/tockycca-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/cca/tockycca-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/cca/tockycca-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/cca/tockycca.jpeg" width="500" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="cca"/><category term="multidimensional"/><category term="motivation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[cca was indeed essential for tocky.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">reflections on my research history</title><link href="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/reflections/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="reflections on my research history"/><published>2024-03-24T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-24T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://monotockylab.github.io/blog/2024/reflections/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was reflecting on my research journey over the past two decades, its challenges and achievements. Today, I want to highlight a crucial factor that guided my research direction and sparked my initial motivation to develop Tocky.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="encountering-with-the-problem">Encountering with the Problem</h4> <p>Launching my PhD at Sakaguchi lab in 2002, I focused on GITR as a potentially useful Treg marker (note this was pre-Foxp3 era). I aimed to replicate early Treg experiments, including the milestone paper <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8760792/">Asano et al., J Exp Med 1996</a> from Shimon Sakaguchi’s group.</p> <p>Asanot et al. claimed that CD25+ T cells do not appear before day 3 post-birth, which assertion was pivotal as it ‘proved’ that ‘depletion of Tregs’ by day 3 thymectomy caused autoimmunity.</p> <p>I obtained a disturbing finding in 2003 (my second year in PhD): substantial numbers of Tregs existed in the neonatal spleen and thymus as early as day 1 after birth. This finding starkly contradicted the key claim of the Treg milestone paper by Asano et al., 1996.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/asano/asano1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/asano/asano1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/asano/asano1-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/asano/asano1.jpg" width="500" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="confirming-the-non-reproducibility">Confirming the Non-Reproducibility</h4> <p>This finding was not isolated – <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/abs/10.1073/pnas.0403303101">Dujardin et al., PNAS, 2004</a> from the Bandeira group presented very similar data to what I had discovered.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/asano/asano2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/asano/asano2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/asano/asano2-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/asano/asano2.jpg" width="700" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="status-quo">Status Quo</h4> <p>At that time, I believed that the Treg theory, which relied heavily on the findings of Asano et al 1996, would soon be revised. Unfortunately, that has not happened.</p> <p>Many textbooks and reviews have echoed the findings of Asano et al, despite the evidence to the contrary regarding neonatal Treg dynamics. More recently, a milestone article on Treg by <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d42859-022-00048-z">Svoboda, Nature, 2022</a> still references the outdated notion as below.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/asano/asano3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/asano/asano3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/asano/asano3-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/asano/asano3.jpg" width="650" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h4 id="redefining-treg-research-beyond-the-boundaries">Redefining Treg Research: Beyond the Boundaries</h4> <p>This experience led me to scrutinize widely accepted papers and theories in the Treg field critically, convincing me that the Treg theories and concepts themselves needed substantial revision.</p> <p>This realization prompted my move from Japan to the UK in 2009 to extend my research and develop new tools to investigate Treg. This endevour resulted in the development of the multidimensional method Canonical Correspondence Analysis (CCA) in genomics <a class="citation" href="#RN98">(Ono et al., 2013)</a> and Tocky <a class="citation" href="#RN55">(Bending et al., 2018)</a>.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="later-development">Later Development</h4> <p>The implications in the issues within Asano et al were profound. I later examined the effects of these and wrote a theoretical/opinion paper, analysing evidence from past papers and proposing a new perspective <a class="citation" href="#RN44">(Ono &amp; Tanaka, 2016)</a>.</p> <p>Further, given that the belief that Tregs constitute a unique lineage of cells originates from, and is supported by, the findings of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8760792/">Asano et al.</a>, it is urgently required to establish a new research framework to investigate Foxp3 and Treg, without relying on the idea of a <em>stable lineage</em>.</p> <p>Our second Tocky publication published in the EMBO Journal <a class="citation" href="#RN56">(Bending et al., 2018)</a> investigated temporal dynamics of Foxp3 transcription and thereby addressed this challenge.</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="treg"/><category term="thymectomy"/><category term="motivation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[reexamining treg fundmentals]]></summary></entry></feed>